Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Bloombergville Now! Archived Website, Jun 3, 2012-Mar 1, 2013
  Bloombergville Now!, established in 2011, is a group against budget cuts in New York City against libraries, education, affordable housing, and other services provided in New York.
- BlueGreen Alliance Archived Website, Jan 7, 2012- ongoing; Blue Green Alliance
  The BlueGreen Alliance, established in 2006, is a national partnership between labor unions and environmental organizations dedicated to expanding the number and quality of jobs in the green economy. They seek to raise awareness of job-creating potential of environmental investments, including solutions to global warming. The alliance accomplishes their work through legislation, education, conferences, and campaigns. The organization is affiliated with numerous labor unions and environmental organizations.
  Employee rights.; Environmental justice.; Job creation.; Labor unions |x Political activity.
- BlueNC Archived Website, May 27, 2012- ongoing; BlueNC
  BlueNC is an independent, collaborative website for culture and politics in North Carolina, not affliated with the Democratic Party. The website contains satirical writings and a blog. The website features a section on Voter Suppression in North Carolina.
- Bluestockings Archived Website, Jul 27, 2009- ongoing; Bluestockings.
  Bluestockings is a radical bookstore, fair trade cafe, and activist center in the Lower East Side of Manhattan. The bookstore is also an educational and activist event space to support movements that challenge hierarchy and oppression. The website holds events listings.
  Anarchism |z New York (State) |z New York.; Bookstores |z New York (State) |z New York.; Feminism |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Bradley Manning Support Network Archived Website, Jul 12, 2013-Oct 10, 2013; Bradley Manning Support Network
  The Bradley Manning Support Network was an organization dedicated to freeing Private Chelsea (formerly Bradley) Manning from serving a 35 year prison sentence for providing classified information to WikiLeaks. In August 2013, the organization changed its name to the Private Manning Support Network when Manning announced she would like to begin to be known publicly by the name of Chelsea Elizabeth Manning, pursue hormone therapy, and be referred to with female pronouns. The website became the Private Manning Support Network in August 2013.
  Manning, Bradley, 1987-; Leaks (Disclosure of information); Whistle blowing |x Law and legislation |z United States.
- Bread and Puppet Archived Website, May 9, 2012- ongoing; Bread and Puppet
  Founded in 1963, the Bread and Puppet Theater is a touring puppet theatre company that focuses its performances radical, political issues, based out of Vermont. The website contains information on their tours, their cheap art philosophy, and their press.
  Puppet plays
- BreaktheChains.info Archived Website, Aug 13, 2010-Aug 12, 2014; BreaktheChains.info
  BreaktheChains.info is a news and discussion forum for supporters of political prisoners, prisoners of war, politicized social prisoners, and victims of police and state intimidation, established in 2006. The forum is updated by members of the disbanded Break the Chains Prisoner Support Network, formerly based in Eugene, Oregon.
  Political prisoners |z United States.; Political prisoners.
- Brecht Forum Archived Website, Aug 15, 2009- ongoing; Brecht Forum (New York, N.Y.).
  The Brecht Forum, originally located at 451 West Street in Manhattan, now at 388 Atlantic Avenue in Brooklyn, is a Marxist cultural and educational center. The Brecht Forum was founded in 1975 as The New York Marxist School. In 1984, the founding collective incorporated as The Brecht Forum with The New York Marxist School as the Forum's core project. In addition to the New York Marxist School, it also offers other programs, language classes, and arts and cultural events. The website contains information on their curriculum and classes, as well as economic news analysis.
  New York Marxist School.; Communism and education.
- Brighton Beach Neighborhood Association, Mar 10, 2012 - ongoing; Brighton Neighborhood Association
  The Brighton Beach Neighborhood Association, founded in 1977, is the housing association of the Brighton Beach neighborhood in Brooklyn, New York City. The association provides housing and health advocacy, landlord assistance, homeowner counseling, tenant organizing, social services, youth services, and economic development. The website contains event listings and action alerts.
  Community organization.; Tenants’ associations.
- Brights' Net Archived Website, Nov 24, 2008 - ongoing; The Brights' Net
  Brights’ Net is the website of the Brights movement, which aims to promote public understanding and acknowledgment of the naturalistic ((free from supernatural and mystical elements) worldview, including equal civil rights and acceptance for people who hold a naturalistic worldview. It was co-founded by Paul Geisert and Mynga Futrell in 2003. The website also provides a community for the movement.
  Secular humanism.
- Brit Tzedek v'Shalom - Jewish Alliance for Justice and Peace Archived Website, Dec 22, 2008- ongoing; Brit Tzedek v'Shalom
  Brit Tzedek v’Shalom, founded in 2002, is a Jewish peace organization that advocated a two-state resolution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict. The organization consisted of approximately 40,000 members organized into a national chapter network, working to educate and advocate for within the Jewish community for a two-state solution and peace in the Middle East. As of January 1, 2010, Brit Tzedek v’Shalom has integrated within the J Street Education Fund.
  Arab-Israeli conflict.; Jews |z United States |x Political activity.; Peace movements |z United States.
- Brooklyn For Peace Archived Website, Mar 7, 2012- ongoing; Brooklyn for Peace
  Brooklyn For Peace was founded in 1984 as Brooklyn Parents for Peace, in response to the U.S invasion of Grenada. Through education on international and domestic issues, the organization works to empower the Brooklyn community to secure a peaceful future for generations to come by building a world where peace is the first response to conflict. They promote U.S. foreign policies based not on coercion and violence, but on peace, justice, democratic advancement, human rights and respect for international law. Their goals include transferring military funds to human needs funds, eliminating nuclear weapons, and resolving conflicts through the United Nations. The website contains information on their working committees, events, and current activities.
  Peace movements |z New York (State) |z New York.; United States |x Foreign relations.
- Bureau Public Secrets Archived Website, Mar 9, 2010- ongoing; Knabb, Ken
  A situationist website, largely consisting of situationist writings in several languages, apparently edited by Ken Knabb.
  Internationale situationniste.
- Business Of Detention Archived Website, Mar 10, 2012-Sep 9, 2012; Business of Detention
  The Business of Detention is a U.S.-based online publication created by reporters Stokely Baksh and Renee Feltz, launched in 2007. The website publishes contemporary immigration detention coverage that grew out of their investigative report on the Corrections Corporation of America in 2008. They sought to present a picture of how the nation’s largest private prison company had partnered with the federal government to detain close to a million undocumented immigrants until they were deported, and in the process fill their empty beds and increase revenue. The website aggregates news on immigration detention.
  Immigrants |x Civil Rights |z United States.; Prison-industrial complex |z United States.; Prisoners |x Civil rights |z United States.; Privatization.
- BuzzFlash Archived Website, Apr 22, 2012- ongoing; BuzzFlash
  BuzzFlash, founded in 2000, is a progressive newswire that provides headlines, commentary, and news analysis to five million people a month. The website contains a link to their parent site, Truth-Out, news, videos, and a blog.
- Cafe Progressive Archived Website, May 28, 2012- ongoing; Cafe Progressive
  Café Progressive is a social justice and environmental activism resource center that provides a guide to progressive sources online. The website displays resources by tags and categories. The website contains social justice and environmental activism sites, blogs, organizations, visionaries, movements and sources for alternative news and information.
  Web portals.
- Campaign for America's Future Archived Website, Jun 12, 2011- ongoing; Institute for America's Future
  The Institute for America’s Future is part of the Campaign for America’s Future, is a strategy center for the progressive movement, whose goal is to create a progressive majority to realize the America of shared prosperity and equal opportunity. The campaign pushes progressive agenda issues that address problems that working families face and educates progressive thinkers, organizers, and community activists. The Institute for America’s Future equips Americans with the tools and information needed to drive issues into the national debate, challenge failed conservative policies and build support for the progressive vision of a government that is on the side of working people. For future captures, please see Campaign for America's Future.
  Equality |x Economic aspects |z United States.; Research institutes |z United States.; Social justice |z United States.
- Campaign for Peace and Democracy Archived Website, Jul 8, 2009- ongoing; Campaign for Peace and Democracy.
  The Campaign for Peace and Democracy, founded in 1982, works to advance a progressive and non-militaristic U.S. foreign policy and is opposition to current U.S. foreign policy. Orginally, the campaign engaged Western peace activists in the defense of the rights of democratic dissidents in the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe, and enlisted East-bloc human rights activists against anti-democratic U.S. policies in countries like Nicaragua and Chile. The majority of the Campaign’s work has been its efforts to work with dissidents and social justice movements worldwide, and to forge alliances between them and progressive movements in the United States. The website contains petitions, endorsements, action alerts, news analysis, and endorsements.
  Human rights.; International cooperation.; Peace movements |z United States.; Social justice.; United States |x Foreign relations.
- Campaign to End the Death Penalty Archived Website, Apr 27, 2012- ongoing; Campaign to End the Death Penalty
  Campaign to End the Death Penalty (CEDP) is a national grassroots organization dedicated to the abolition of capital punishment. CEDP works with specific cases to free innocent men on death row through education, outreach, protests, and events, like their "Live from Death Row" event. They also hold an annual convention. The website contains information on chapters, their newsletter, action alerts, multimedia, information on prisoners, and other news.
  Capital punishment.
- Campaign to Stop Killer Coke Archived Website, Dec 2, 2010- ongoing; Campaign to Stop Killer Coke
  The Campaign to Stop Killer Coke is a worldwide movement based on the efforts of thousands of volunteers. Ray Rogers is the director of the Campaign to Stop Killer Coke. His organization, Corporate Campaign, Inc., created the Campaign to Stop Killer Coke to hold The Coca-Cola Company, its bottlers and subsidiaries accountable and to end the gruesome cycle of violence including the systematic intimidation, kidnapping, torture and murder of union leaders and members of their families in efforts to crush their unions, particularly in Colombia and Guatemala.
  Coca-Cola Company.; Employee rights |z Columbia.; Employee rights |z Guatemala; Human rights |z Colombia.; Human rights |z Guatemala.; Social responsibility of business.
- Camp Delta Standard Operating Procedure Archived Website, Nov 21, 2007-Jul 12, 2009; Wikileaks
  Contains the United States Dept. of Defense Joint Task Force Guantanamo (JTF-GTMO) standard operating procedures (SOP) for Camp Delta (Guantanamo Bay prison), 2003 and related documents. This is the primary document for the operation of Guantanamo bay, including the securing and treatment of detainees. The document is extensive and includes, in addition to text various forms, identity cards and even Muslim burial instructions. It is signed by Major General Miller, who Donald Rumsfeld later sent to Abu Ghraib to "Gitmoize it". The document is also the subject of an ongoing legal action between the ACLU, which has been trying to obtain it, and the Department of Defense, which has withheld it in full. Wikileaks is a multi-jurisdictional organization to protect internal dissidents, whistleblowers, journalists and bloggers who face legal or other threats related to publishing. Wikileaks provides a forum for the entire global community to relentlessly examine any document for its credibility, plausibility, veracity and validity.
  Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners and prisons, American.
- Camp Kinderland Archived Website, Apr 1, 2012- ongoing; Camp Kinderland
  Camp Kinderland was founded on Sylvan Lake in Hopewell Junction, NY in 1923 by members of the Workmen’s Circle who worked in the organization’s New York City schools. The camp’s founders sought to create a summer youth camp that would not only provide a recreational escape for the children of working people from the tenements of New York City, but also one whose culture would encourage and foster a commitment to socially progressive activism and the embracing of a rich Jewish secular tradition. The website contains news and event listings, camper and parent resources, and information about renting their facilities.
  Camps |x Massachusetts.; Jewish Children |z United States.
- Campus Activism Archived Website, Feb 20, 2012- ongoing; Campus Activism
  CampusActivism.org, established in 2002, operates as a networking tool and database for student activists. The website works with activists to share contact information, event information, ideas, and resources. The website contains tools to add and browse email lists, campaign notices, issues, events, contacts, groups, and resources.
  Student movements |z United States.
- Campus Progress Archived Website, Oct 9, 2011-Oct 7, 2013; Center for American Progress
  Campus Progress is a national organization that works with and for young people to promote progressive solutions to key political and social challenges, with a special emphasis on access and other issues related to college education.
  Access to higher education |z United States.; College students |x Political activity |z United States.; Education, Higher |z United States.; Student movements |z United States.
- Center for American Progress Action Fund Archived Website, Oct 7, 2011-present
  The Center for American Progress Action Fund, founded in 2003, is a progressive public policy research and advocacy organization. Their mission is to transform progressive ideas into policy through rapid response communications, legislative action, grassroots organizing and advocacy, and partnerships with other progressive leaders. Their projects include ThinkProgress [captured in Alternative Media collection], the American Worker Project, and the Campus Progress Action project [captured in Education and Student Movements collection]. The website contains news and publications related to the organization and event listings.
- Center for Constitutional Rights Cases: Illegal Detentions and Guantanamo Archived Website, Jun 24, 2011- ongoing; Center for Constitutional Rights (New York, N.Y.).
  Contains websites of cases taken by the Center for Constitutional Rights in relation to illegal detention and the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp
  Human rights |z United States.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Moral and ethical aspects |z United States.; Torture |z United States.
- Center for Constitutional Rights Archived Website, Feb 7, 2007 - ongoing; Center for Constitutional Rights (New York, N.Y.).
  The Center for Constitutional Rights (CCR), founded in 1966 by attorneys who represented civil rights movements in the South, is dedicated to advancing and protecting the rights guaranteed by the United States Constitution and the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. CCR is a non-profit legal and educational organization committed to the use of law as a force for social change. Some issues CCR works on is illegal detention and Guantanamo, surveillance and attacks on dissent, criminal justice and mass incarcerations, corporate human rights abuse, government abuse of power, racial and gender justice, and international law and accountability. The website lists news and current cases. Note that the CCR’s records are at the Tamiment Library.
  Civil rights |z United States.; Human rights.
- Center for Democracy & Technology Archived Website, Jul 17, 2011- ongoing; Center for Democracy & Technology
  The Center for Democracy and Technology is a non-profit public interest civil liberties organization working to keep the Internet open, innovative, and free, using its expertise in law, technology, and policy. CDT works to enhance free expression and privacy in communications technologies while protecting civil liberties, and develops and works to implement policies that will keep the Internet open, innovative and free.
  Cyberspace |x Political aspects.; Freedom of information.; Internet |x Political aspects.; World Wide Web |x Political aspects.
- Center for Media Justice Archived Website, Oct 20, 2011- ongoing; Center for Media Justice
  Founded in 2002, the Center for Media Justice is a progressive communications strategy and media policy tank for grassroots organizations serving communities of color and America’s poor. Their mission is to create media and cultural conditions that strengthen movements for racial justice, economic equity, and human rights. The Center has three main programs, the Justice Communication Program, MAG-Net, and the Media Justice Policy Program.
  Community organization.; Mass media criticism.; Minorities--United States.; Social justice.
- Center for Popular Economics (CPE) Archived Website, Oct 28, 2009 - Nov 2, 2012; Center for Popular Economics
  The Center for Popular Economics, founded in 1979 based in Amherst, MA, is a non-profit collective of over 80 economists, dedicated to building a just, sustainable and viable economy. They examine root causes of economic inequality and injustice including systems of oppression based on race, class, gender, nation and ethnicity. They work to make education on economics more understandable and accessible. The website publishes a newsletter and other publications, news, and hosts workshops and institutes. NOTE: This site's capture schedule has been turned off. More current captures can be found in our Economic and Social Justice web archive.
  Economics |z United States.; Social justice |z United States.; United States |x Economic conditions.
- Center for Popular Economics Archived Website, May 3, 2011- ongoing; Center for Popular Economics
  The Center for Popular Economics is a non-profit collective of progressive political economists, all dedicated to building a just, sustainable and viable economy. The center is based in Amherst, MA and was founded in 1979. The center hosts workshops and institutes and produces publications that demystify the economy and give economic tools to people fighting for social and economic justice.
  Economists.; Labor economics.; Marxian economics.; Welfare economics.
- Center for Story-based Strategy Archived Website, Jul 8, 2013- ongoing; Center for Story-based Strategy (CSS)
  Founded in 2002, the Center for Story-based Strategy (CSS) offers tools, training, and strategy support to organizations and movements working for social and ecological justice and social change. The Strategy and Training Project is a nonprofit collective that works to apply meme theory and a narrative analysis of power to strengthen social change efforts. The website contains a blog, training materials, and information on projects. They were formerly known as smartMeme.
  Computer network resources.; Internet |x Political aspects.; Memes.
- Center for the Study of Political Graphics Archived Website, May 11, 2012- ongoing; Center for the Study of Political Graphics
  The Center for the Study of Political Graphics collects, preserves, and exhibits posters relating to historical and contemporary movements for social change. CSPG demonstrates the power and significance of these artistic expressions of social change through traveling exhibitions, lectures, publications, and workshops. They have over 75,000 posters from the Russian Revolution to the present day. The website contains virtual exhibits, weekly poster posts, and a print shop.
  Political posters.
- Center for The Working Poor Archived Website, Mar 23, 2010- ongoing; Center for the Working Poor
  Founded in 2006, The Center for the Working Poor is an inter-faith intentional community inspired by the Catholic Worker movement and New Monasticism, and which is committed to strategic non-violent social change. The Center shares a vision of non-violent social change to benefit the most oppressed in our society. Volunteer members run the Center for the Working Poor, which is a non-profit that provides social services, and organizes protest, including civil disobedience actions, hunger strikes, and other forms of strategic non-violence. Also part of the website is their newspaper, the Burning Bush.
  Poor |z United States; Working class |z United States.
- Central New York Reds Archived Website, Apr 28, 2013- ongoing; Central New York Reds
  Central New York Reds is the website for the Socialist Party of Central New York. The organization holds regular Socialist forums to discuss and debate important topics and to include radical perspective, organize protests, and other activities. The website contains event listings, information about their platform, resources, and a blog.
  Socialism |z New York (State).
- Chelsea Manning Support Network Archived Website, Jul 19, 2014-ongoing; Bradley Manning Support Network; Private Manning Support Network
  The Chelsea Manning Support Network is an organization dedicated to freeing Private Chelsea (formerly Bradley) Manning from serving a 35 year prison sentence for providing classified information to WikiLeaks. In August 2013, the organization changed its name when Manning announced she would like to begin to be known publicly by the name of Chelsea Elizabeth Manning, pursue hormone therapy, and be referred to with female pronouns. In 2014, the organization changed its name from the Private Manning Support Network to the Chelsea Manning Support Network. The organization raises funds for Manning, posts news about Manning and on other cases related to government surveillance and whistle-blowing, as well as a campaign to pardon Manning. The website also contains a significant amount of information on the trial that took place in 2013.
- Citizens For Tax Justice Archived Website, Jan 11, 2012- ongoing; Citizens for Tax Justice
  Citizens for Tax Justice (CTJ), founded in 1979, is a public interest research and advocacy organization focusing on federal, state and local tax policies and their impact upon the United States. CTJ works to give citizens a voice in new tax laws, fairer taxes for middle and low income families, closing corporate tax loopholes, reducing the federal debt, promoting funding for government services, and other campaigns promoting tax justice.
  Progressive taxation |z United States.; Taxation--United States.